Guide to the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Frederick W. Hilles Papers, 1775–1979; Series II; 52.53; 107 boxes + 1 broadside, 1 roll.
  - Personal and Family Papers, 1775–1976
    - Financial and Personal Records, 1775–1965
      - Frederick W. and Susan Morse Hilles, 1917–1976
        - Pansy Patch Farm, 1936 (Box 148 (Broadside), Folder 1790)
          Blueprint of Pansy Patch Farm
        - Property and ownership, 1942–1952 (Box 116, Folder 1642)
          FWH and SMH property and wills
        - Property and ownership, 1949 (Box 147 (Oversize), Folder 1786)
          Architectural drawings of the Hilles house.
        - Receipts, 1929–1968 (Box 116, Folder 1643-1645)
        - Receipts, 1929–1968 (Box 117, Folder 1646-1650)
        - Receipts, 1929–1968 (Box 118, Folder 1651-1652)
        - Susan Morse Hilles Trust, 1946–1956 (Box 118, Folder 1653)
        - Frederick W. Hilles, Jr. birth certificate, 1938 (Box 118, Folder 1654)
        - Frederick W. Hilles, Jr. graduation from St. Lawrence University, 1959 (Box 147 (Oversize), Folder 1787)
          Includes a graduation program, a photograph of F. W. Hilles, Jr., and a diploma.
        - Travel chess set, undated (Box 121, Folder 1678)
        - Appraised inventory of books owned by the Hilles family, undated (Box 135, Folder 1732)
        - Bookends made from books, undated (Box 135, Folder 1733)
        - Notes and research material removed from books (Box 135, Folder 1734-1747)
          Includes notes, receipts, and postcards.
    - Photographs, 1936–1973
      - C. D. Hilles, 1936; undated (Box 118, Folder 1655-1656)
      - C. D. Hilles, undated (Box 147 (Oversize), Folder 1788)
      - Events, undated (Box 118, Folder 1657)
        Includes an event at the Beinecke Library displaying Sir Joshua Reynolds' court suit.
      - Frederick W. Hilles army portraits, undated (Box 118, Folder 1658)
      - Christmas, 1973; undated (Box 118, Folder 1659)
      - Family, 1938–1973 (Box 119, Folder 1660-1663)
      - Family, undated (Box 147 (Oversize), Folder 1789)
      - William Howard Taft, undated (Box 119, Folder 1664)
      - Vacations, 1972–1973; undated (Box 119, Folder 1665-1668)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 119, Folder 1669)
    - Notebooks and Planners, 1919–1967
      - Address book, undated (Box 119, Folder 1670)
      - Album, undated (Box 119, Folder 1671)
      - Album, undated (Box 134, Folder 1728)
      - Date books, 1956 (Box 120, Folder 1672)
      - Dealer catalogs clippings, undated (Box 120, Folder 1673)
      - Filing book, undated (Box 145 (Oversize), Folder 1780)
      - Letters of recommendation, 1959–1967 (Box 120, Folder 1674)
        Contains letters of recommendation by Frederick W. Hilles for colleagues.
      - Military service records, 1943–1946 (Box 120, Folder 1675)
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 134, Folder 1729-1731)
        Two empty notebooks and one partially completed notebook.
      - Theatre programs, 1953–1962 (Box 120, Folder 1676)
      - Theatre scrapbook, 1918–1919 (Box 120, Folder 1677)
        Contains show clippings.
      - Travel notebooks, 1922; 1953; undated (Box 121, Folder 1679-1681)
      - Travel notebook of Susan Morse Hilles, undated (Box 121, Folder 1682)
      - Yale course books and expense books, 1919–1921 (Box 121, Folder 1683)
  - Books, 1949–1975
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 122, Folder 1684-1686)
      Books owned by Hilles, many of them annotated, including material on Samuel Johnson, James Boswell, Mary Palmer Reynolds, Horace Walpole, English drama and poetry, Edmund Burke, Thomas and Jane Welsh Carlyle, John Wilkes, Bertolt Brecht, World War I, Oliver Goldsmith, William Wordsworth, and Alexander Pope. Also includes an unidentified volume in Arabic in box 129.
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 123, Folder 1687-1689)
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 124, Folder 1690-1692)
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 125, Folder 1693-1695)
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 126, Folder 1696-1698)
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 127, Folder 1699-1702)
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 128, Folder 1703-1706)
    - Books, 1837–1975 (Box 129, Folder 1707-1711)
    - Books (Box 130, Folder 1712-1716)
      Social registers and manuals owned by Hilles, including registers for the Grolier Club, Old Lyme Country Club, the Cosmopolitan Club, the Somerset Club, and the Century Association. Also includes a diary and manual for the Real Estate Board of New York and two volumes of the Social Register of New York.
    - Books (Box 131, Folder 1717-1719)
    - Books (Box 132, Folder 1720-1725)
      Educational books and pamphlets, including material pertaining to the Yale Club and Yale University, Skull and Bones, and the Walker School for Girls.
    - Books (Box 133, Folder 1726-1727)
  - Restricted Papers
    - Student evaluations and papers, 4 folders (Box 150)
      Restricted until 2039. For further information consult appropriate curator.
  - Restricted Fragile Papers
    - Christmas album (Box 150)
      Spanish Pavilion Season's Greetings recorded sound album.
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.